Guide to the Department of Epidemiology and Public Health, Yale University, Records
Yale University. Department of Manuscripts and Archives
Department of Epidemiology and Public Health, Yale University, records
1934-2016
RU 268
Yale University. Department of Manuscripts and Archives
231
The records consist of correspondence and administrative files documenting the operations and activities of the School of Epidemiology and Public Health (a department within the Yale School of Medicine). Materials include an administrative subject-correspondence file, curriculum and student records, surveys, hospital administration materials, financial papers and grants, student and course files, and information on the Edwin Weinerman Memorial Fund.
Yale University. School of Medicine
General note
Forms part of Yale Record Group 27-I (YRG 27-I), Records of Yale School of Epidemiology and Public Health.
Conditions Governing Access
Access to the records is partially restricted. See Collection Contents for details.
Arrangement
The records are arranged in seven series: I. Departmental Subject-Correspondence Files, 1940-1960. II. Curricular and Student Data, 1938-1960. III. Surveys, 1924-1958. IV. Hospital Administration, 1945-1960. V. Finances and Grants, 1952-1960. VI. Course Files, 1962-1970. VII. Weinerman Memorial Fund, 1968-1975; and subsequent accessions.
Scope and Contents
Series I, Departmental Subject-Correspondence Files, 1940-1960, were organized and maintained by the Department of Public Health beginning approximately with Ira Hiscock"s chairmanship in 1945 and ending when the Department was reorganized as the Department of Epidemiology and Public Health in 1960-1961. The records are organized chronologically by fiscal year, beginning with the incomplete records of July 1, 1946-June 30, 1947.
Series II, Curriculum and Student Data, 1938-1960, contains material relating to the Department"s course offerings and students. The sections of the series containing student files are restricted under the 75 year policy governing access to student records. Curriculum records include required reading lists, class schedules, course lists, and other printed matter. For earlier curriculum records see the Winslow and Hiscock Papers.
Series III, Surveys, 1924-1958, contains correspondence, data and findings from approximately 30 health care surveys conducted by students and faculty of the Department of Public Health. The information contained in this series is incomplete for most of the communities, but there is extensive material for several of the surveys: Bristol, Connecticut; Eastern Windham County, Connecticut; Hartford, Connecticut; and St. Louis, Missouri. The surveys are arranged alphabetically by city and alphabetically by subject within a given city.
Series IV, Hospital Administration, 1945-1946, contains records relating to the Hospital Administration course, a field of study within the Department of Public Health. The administrative papers of George Buis, director of the Hospital Administration course and other faculty members involved in the program are incorporated into the series. The records are arranged chronologically and by subject within the chronology.
Series V, Finances and Grants, 1952-1960, contains miscellaneous financial records: statements, expense and equipment account data, and records pertaining to research grants 1955-1959.
Series VI, Course Files, 1962-1970, contains documentation on courses taught by the Department's faculty, particularly E. R. Weinerman and I. S. Falk.
Series VII, Weinerman Memorial Fund, 1968-1975, is composed of the Fund's administrative records and miscellaneous Weinerman biographical material.
Hospitals; Public health -- Study and teaching; Universities and colleges -- Administration; Universities and colleges -- Departments; Universities and colleges -- Finance; Yale University -- Administration; Yale University -- Curricula; Yale University -- Finance; Yale University -- Students; Yale University. Department of Epidemiology and Public Health; Yale University. School of Medicine
- Departmental Files, 1940-1960; Series I
  Conditions Governing Access
  The materials are open for research.
  - 1940-1945
    - Alumni: correspondence, 1945 (Box 1, Folder 1)
    - Alumni: lists, 1940 (Box 1, Folder 2)
    - East, Mrs. Leona Dept. of Health, Illinois, 1943-1944 (Box 1, Folder 3)
    - Goldman, Franz: Associate Clinical Professor of Public Health, 1945 (Box 1, Folder 4)
    - Medical Affairs, Director of, 1946 (Box 1, Folder 5)
    - Medical Social Service Miss Elizabeth Rice, 1945 (Box 1, Folder 6)
    - Nelbach, Philip E.: Assistant Professor of Public Health, 1944-1945 (Box 1, Folder 7)
    - Paul, John R. Preventive Medicine, Department of, 1943-1945 (Box 1, Folder 8)
    - Photograph: Dept. of Public Health, Faculty and Staff, 1943-1944 (Box 1, Folder 9)
    - President's office, 1945-1946 (Box 1, Folder 10)
    - Provost's office, 1945-1948 (Box 1, Folder 11)
    - Radio Committee, 1945 (Box 1, Folder 12)
    - Registrar, Miss Dasey, 1945 (Box 1, Folder 13)
    - Special Account: Watkins, J.H., 1940-1942 (Box 1, Folder 14)
    - Staff meetings, 1942-1943 (Box 1, Folder 15)
    - Suttie, Roscoe: Member of Civil Engineering Department, 1945 (Box 1, Folder 16)
    - Watkins, John H.: Member of Public Health Department, 1945 (Box 1, Folder 17)
    - Yale University: courses, 1943-1945 (Box 1, Folder 18)
    - Surveys: Inquiries, 1946-1947 (Box 2, Folder 19)
    - Survey: Columbus, Oh., 1946-1947 (Box 2, Folder 20)
    - American Medical Association, 1946-1947 (Box 2, Folder 21)
    - American Public Health Association, 1946-1947 (Box 2, Folder 22-23)
      - Administration practice, 1946 (Box 2, Folder 24)
      - American Journal of Public Health, 1946-1947 (Box 2, Folder 25)
      - Committee on Motion Pictures, 1946-1947 (Box 2, Folder 26)
      - Committee on State Health Studies, 1946-1947 (Box 2, Folder 27)
    - American Red Cross: Medical Advisory Committee, 1946-1947 (Box 2, Folder 28)
    - American Red Cross: New Haven Chapter, 1946-1947 (Box 2, Folder 29)
    - Association of Schools of Public Health, 1946-1947 (Box 2, Folder 30)
    - Commonwealth Fund, 1946-1947 (Box 2, Folder 31)
    - Community Chests and Councils, Inc., 1946-1947 (Box 2, Folder 32)
    - Connecticut State Department of Health: Commissioner, 1946-1947 (Box 3, Folder 33)
    - Connecticut State Medical Society: Hezekiah Beardsley Club (Hetzel), 1946-1947 (Box 3, Folder 34)
    - Connecticut State Medical Society: Academy of Pediatrics, State Study Committee (Root), 1946-1947 (Box 3, Folder 35)
    - Hawaii, 1946-1947 (Box 3, Folder 36)
    - Institute of Inter-American Affairs, 1946-1947 (Box 3, Folder 37)
    - Kellogg Foundation, 1946-1947 (Box 3, Folder 38)
    - Milbank Memorial Fund, 1946-1947 (Box 3, Folder 39)
    - National Dairy Council, 1946-1947 (Box 3, Folder 40)
    - National Foundation for Infantile Paralysis, 1946-1947 (Box 3, Folder 41)
    - National Foundation for Infantile Paralysis: New Haven Chapter, 1946-1947 (Box 3, Folder 42)
    - National Health Council, 1946-1947 (Box 3, Folder 43)
    - National Health Council: Voluntary Health Agencies Study, 1946-1947 (Box 3, Folder 44)
    - National Health Council: National Social Welfare Assembly, 1946-1947 (Box 3, Folder 45)
    - National Organization for Public Health Nursing, 1946-1947 (Box 4, Folder 46)
    - National Research Council, 1946-1947 (Box 4, Folder 47)
    - National Research Council: Pacific Science Conference, 1946-1947 (Box 4, Folder 48)
    - National Sanitation Foundation, 1946-1947 (Box 4, Folder 49)
    - National Society for the Prevention of Blindness, 1946-1947 (Box 4, Folder 50-52)
      - 1946 September 1 (Box 4, Folder 53)
      - Committee on Program (Plan and Scope) (Box 4, Folder 54)
    - National Tuberculosis Association, 1946-1947 (Box 5, Folder 55-57)
      - Connecticut Tuberculosis Association (Box 5, Folder 58)
      - New Haven Tuberculosis Association (E.T.R.A.) (Box 5, Folder 59)
      - Planning Committee, Third National Conference on College Health (Box 5, Folder 60)
    - New Haven Board of Health, 1946-1947 (Box 5, Folder 61)
    - New Haven Board of Health: minutes of meetings, 1946-1947 (Box 5, Folder 62)
    - New Haven Board of Health: Health Education Committee, 1946-1947 (Box 6, Folder 63)
    - New Haven Council of Social Agencies, 1946-1947 (Box 6, Folder 64)
    - New Haven Hospital, 1946-1947 (Box 6, Folder 65)
    - New Haven Visiting Nurse Association, 1946-1947 (Box 6, Folder 66)
    - Rockefeller Foundation, 1946-1947 (Box 6, Folder 67)
    - United States Army, 1946-1947 (Box 6, Folder 68)
    - United States Public Health Service, 1946-1947, 1946 September 1 (Box 6, Folder 69-70)
    - United States Public Health Service: Bolton Fellowships, 1946-1947 (Box 6, Folder 71)
    - Health Departments (City, County, State), 1946-1947 (Box 6, Folder 72)
    - Health Departments: New York City Health Dept., 1946-1947 (Box 6, Folder 73)
    - Health Departments: Kansas State Dept. of Health, 1946-1947 (Box 6, Folder 74)
    - Health Departments: Mississippi State Board of Health, 1946-1947 (Box 6, Folder 75)
    - Widdemer, Kenneth D.(Health Council of Greater New York), 1946-1947 (Box 6, Folder 76)
  - 1947-1948
    - General A (Box 7, Folder 77-79)
    - General B (Box 7, Folder 80-81)
    - General C (Box 7, Folder 82)
    - General C (Box 8, Folder 83-84)
    - General D (Box 8, Folder 85)
    - General E (Box 8, Folder 86)
    - General F (Box 8, Folder 87-88)
    - General G (Box 9, Folder 89)
    - General H (Box 9, Folder 90-92)
    - General I (Box 9, Folder 93)
    - General J (Box 9, Folder 94)
    - General K (Box 9, Folder 95)
    - General L (Box 9, Folder 96)
    - General M (Box 9, Folder 97)
    - General M (Box 10, Folder 98-99)
    - General N (Box 10, Folder 100-103)
    - General O (Box 11, Folder 104)
    - General P (Box 11, Folder 105)
    - General R (Box 11, Folder 106-107)
    - General S (Box 11, Folder 108)
    - General T (Box 11, Folder 109-110)
    - General U (Box 11, Folder 111)
    - General V (Box 11, Folder 112)
    - General W (Box 12, Folder 113-114)
    - General Y (Box 12, Folder 115-116)
    - General Z (Box 12, Folder 117)
    - I.V. Hiscock - Administration, 1947-1948 (Box 13, Folder 118)
      - Hospital Administration Plan, 1947-1948 (Box 13, Folder 119-122)
      - Dr. C. Clay, 1947-1948 (Box 13, Folder 123)
    - G.R. Cowgill - Nutrition, 1947-1948 (Box 13, Folder 124)
    - G.H. Dession - Law, 1947-1948 (Box 13, Folder 125)
    - J.R. Paul - Preventive Medicine, 1947-1948 (Box 13, Folder 126)
      - Conference of Professors of Preventive Medicine, 1947-1948 (Box 13, Folder 127)
    - R.H. Suttie - Sanitary Engineering, 1947-1948 (Box 13, Folder 128)
    - L. Greenburg - Industrial Hygiene, 1947-1948 (Box 13, Folder 129)
    - Occupational Medicine and Hygiene - Dr. Buchan, 1947-1948 (Box 14, Folder 130-131)
    - P.B. Cowles - Bacteriology, 1947-1948 (Box 14, Folder 132)
    - J.H. Watkins - Statistics, 1947-1948 (Box 14, Folder 133)
    - F. Goldman - Medical Care (Box 14, Folder 134)
      - Plan for Training in Medical Care Administration at Yale, 1947-1948 (Box 14, Folder 135)
      - Committee of Physicians for the Improvement of Medical Care, Inc., 1947-1948 (Box 14, Folder 136)
    - M.A. Pond - Sanitation of Environment, 1947-1948 (Box 14, Folder 137)
    - E.P. Rice - Social Service, 1947-1948 (Box 14, Folder 138)
    - C.C. Wilson - School Health, 1947-1948 (Box 14, Folder 139)
    - A. Foord - Child Health and Personal Hygiene, 1947-1948 (Box 14, Folder 140)
    - Other Staff Members, 1947-1948 (Box 14, Folder 141)
      - S.S. Lifson, 1947-1948 (Box 14, Folder 142)
      - F.P. Mathews, 1947-1948 (Box 14, Folder 143)
      - Leonid S. Snegireff, 1947-1948 (Box 14, Folder 144)
    - Former Staff Members, 1947-1948 (Box 14, Folder 145)
    - Staff meetings, 1947-1948 (Box 15, Folder 146)
      - Yale Medical School staff Conference, 1947-1948 (Box 15, Folder 147)
    - Other public health fields: nursing, 1947-1948 (Box 15, Folder 148)
    - President"s office, 1947-1948 (Box 15, Folder 149)
    - Director of Medical Affairs, 1947-1948 (Box 15, Folder 150)
    - Provost"s office, 1947-1948 (Box 15, Folder 151)
    - Treasurer"s office, 1947-1948 (Box 15, Folder 152)
    - Recommendations for appointment, 1947-1948 (Box 15, Folder 153)
    - Dean - Graduate School, 1947-1948 (Box 15, Folder 154)
    - Assistant Dean - Graduate School, 1947-1948 (Box 15, Folder 155)
    - Registrar - Graduate School, 1947-1948 (Box 15, Folder 156)
    - Dean - Medical School, 1947-1948 (Box 15, Folder 157)
      - Committee on Clinical Sciences and Practice, 1947-1948 (Box 15, Folder 158)
    - Assistant Dean - Medical School, 1947-1948 (Box 15, Folder 159)
      - Committee on Admissions - Medical School, 1947-1948 (Box 15, Folder 160)
    - Executive Secretary - Medical School, 1947-1948 (Box 15, Folder 161)
    - Registrar - Medical School, 1947-1948 (Box 15, Folder 162)
    - Engineering school, 1947-1948 (Box 16, Folder 163)
    - Department of Education, 1947-1948 (Box 16, Folder 164)
    - School of Nursing, 1947-1948 (Box 16, Folder 165)
    - University Library, 1947-1948 (Box 16, Folder 166)
    - Medical School Library, 1947-1948 (Box 16, Folder 167)
    - Association of Internes and Medical Students, 1947-1948 (Box 16, Folder 168)
    - Nominations for Honors and Awards, 1947-1948 (Box 16, Folder 169)
    - Delta Omega, 1947-1948 (Box 16, Folder 170)
    - Yale University Catalogue, 1947-1948 (Box 16, Folder 171)
    - University Committees
      - Board of Permanent Officers - Medical School, 1947-1948 (Box 16, Folder 172-173)
      - Board of Permanent Officers - S.S.S., 1947-1948 (Box 16, Folder 174)
      - Committee on Adult Education, 1947-1948 (Box 16, Folder 175)
      - Department of University Health, 1947-1948 (Box 16, Folder 176)
      - Institute on Occupational Medicine and Hygiene, 1947-1948 (Box 16, Folder 177)
      - Department of Psychiatry and Mental Hygiene, 1947-1948 (Box 16, Folder 178)
      - Bishop Museum Committee, 1947-1948 (Box 17, Folder 179)
      - Committee on Medical Affairs, 1947-1948 (Box 17, Folder 180)
      - Committee on Physical Medicine, 1947-1948 (Box 17, Folder 181)
      - Rehabilitation Study Unit, 1947-1948 (Box 17, Folder 182)
    - Public Health Department - General, 1947-1948 (Box 17, Folder 183)
    - General
      - Inquiries about courses (see Prospective Students), 1947-1948 (Box 17, Folder 184)
      - Accreditation Plan, 1947-1948 (Box 17, Folder 185)
      - Committee on Admissions, 1947-1948 (Box 17, Folder 186)
      - Newsletter, 1947-1948 (Box 17, Folder 187)
      - Publishers, 1947-1948 (Box 17, Folder 188)
      - Recommendations for jobs, 1947-1948 (Box 17, Folder 189)
      - Requests for candidates for jobs, 1947-1948 (Box 17, Folder 190-191)
      - Visiting lecturers, 1947-1948 (Box 18, Folder 192)
      - Field trips, 1947-1948 (Box 18, Folder 193)
      - Annual reports, 1947-1948 (Box 18, Folder 194)
      - Winslow Number, Yale Journal of Biology and Medicine, 1947-1948 (Box 18, Folder 195-196)
      - Health legislation, 1947-1948 (Box 18, Folder 197)
    - Surveys
      - Methods, 1947-1948 (Box 18, Folder 198)
      - Inquiries, 1947-1948 (Box 18, Folder 199)
      - Columbus, Ohio, 1947-1948 (Box 18, Folder 200)
      - Washington D.C., 1947-1948 (Box 18, Folder 201)
      - Fairfield, Conn., 1947-1948 (Box 18, Folder 202)
      - Dayton, Ohio, 1947-1948 (Box 18, Folder 203)
      - Rockville, Conn., 1947-1948 (Box 19, Folder 204)
      - Rhode Island, 1947-1948 (Box 19, Folder 205)
    - R.O.T.C., 1947-1948 (Box 19, Folder 206)
    - American Dental Association, 1947-1948 (Box 19, Folder 207)
    - American Epidemiological Society, 1947-1948 (Box 19, Folder 208)
    - American Medical Association, 1947-1948 (Box 19, Folder 209)
    - American Public Health Association, 1947-1948 (Box 19, Folder 210-212)
    - American Public Health Association, 1947-1948 (Box 20, Folder 213)
      - American Journal of Public Health, 1947-1948 (Box 20, Folder 214)
      - Committee on Motion Pictures, 1947-1948 (Box 20, Folder 215)
      - Committee on State Health Studies, 1947-1948 (Box 20, Folder 216-218)
      - Committee on Eligibility, 1947-1948 (Box 20, Folder 219)
      - Committee on Professional Education, 1947-1948 (Box 20, Folder 220)
      - Committee on Administrative Practice, 1947-1948 (Box 21, Folder 221-222)
      - Annual meeting, 1947-1948 (Box 21, Folder 223)
      - Connecticut Public Health Association, 1947-1948 (Box 21, Folder 224)
      - Sanitation project, 1947-1948 (Box 21, Folder 225)
    - American Red Cross, 1947-1948 (Box 21, Folder 226)
      - National, 1947-1948 (Box 22, Folder 227-228)
      - Medical Advisory Committee, 1947-1948 (Box 22, Folder 229)
      - New Haven Chapter, 1947-1948 (Box 22, Folder 230)
    - American Social Hygiene Association, 1947-1948 (Box 22, Folder 231)
    - Association of Schools of Public Health, 1947-1948 (Box 22, Folder 232)
      - California, 1947-1948 (Box 22, Folder 233)
      - Columbia, 1947-1948 (Box 22, Folder 234)
      - Harvard, 1947-1948 (Box 22, Folder 235)
      - Johns Hopkins, 1947-1948 (Box 22, Folder 236)
      - Michigan, 1947-1948 (Box 23, Folder 237)
      - Minnesota, 1947-1948 (Box 23, Folder 238)
      - New York, 1947-1948 (Box 23, Folder 239)
      - North Carolina, 1947-1948 (Box 23, Folder 240)
      - Toronto, 1947-1948 (Box 23, Folder 241)
    - Boy Scouts of America, 1947-1948 (Box 23, Folder 242-243)
    - Chamber of Commerce, 1947-1948 (Box 23, Folder 244)
    - Commonwealth Fund, 1947-1948 (Box 23, Folder 245-246)
    - Community Chests and Councils, Inc., 1947-1948 (Box 23, Folder 247)
    - Commonwealth Fund: Community Health Organization Revision, 1947-1948 (Box 23, Folder 248)
    - Connecticut Cancer Society, 1947-1948 (Box 23, Folder 249)
    - Connecticut Cancer Society, 1947-1948 (Box 24, Folder 250-251)
    - Connecticut Society for Mental Hygiene, 1947-1948 (Box 24, Folder 252)
      - New Haven Mental Hygiene Society, 1947-1948 (Box 24, Folder 253)
    - Connecticut State Department of Health, 1947-1948 (Box 24, Folder 254)
      - Commissioner, 1947-1948 (Box 24, Folder 255)
      - Commissioner; Stanley H. Osborne Day, 1947-1948 (Box 24, Folder 256)
      - Preventable diseases, 1947-1948 (Box 24, Folder 257)
      - Tuberculosis Comm., 1947-1948 (Box 24, Folder 258)
    - Connecticut State Department of Education, 1947-1948 (Box 24, Folder 259)
    - Connecticut State Medical Society, 1947-1948 (Box 24, Folder 260)
      - Connecticut Medical Service, 1947-1948 (Box 24, Folder 261)
      - Academy of Pediatrics - State Study Committee (Root), 1947-1948 (Box 24, Folder 262)
    - Hawaii, 1947-1948 (Box 24, Folder 263)
    - Institute of Inter-American Affairs, 1947-1948 (Box 25, Folder 264)
    - Kellogg Foundation, 1947-1948 (Box 25, Folder 265)
      - Lasker Foundation, 1947-1948 (Box 25, Folder 266)
    - Milbank Memorial Fund, 1947-1948 (Box 25, Folder 267)
    - National Association of Housing Officials, 1947-1948 (Box 25, Folder 268)
    - National Dairy Council, 1947-1948 (Box 25, Folder 269)
    - National Education Association, 1947-1948 (Box 25, Folder 270)
    - National Foundation for Infantile Paralysis, 1947-1948 (Box 25, Folder 271-272)
      - New Haven Chapter, 1947-1948 (Box 25, Folder 273)
    - National Health Council, 1947-1948 (Box 25, Folder 274-276)
    - National Health Council, 1947-1948 (Box 26, Folder 277)
      - Voluntary Health Agencies Study, 1947-1948 (Box 26, Folder 278)
      - National Social Welfare Assembly, 1947-1948 (Box 26, Folder 279-281)
    - National Organization for Public Health Nursing, 1947-1948 (Box 26, Folder 282)
    - National Organization for Public Health Nursing, 1947-1948 (Box 27, Folder 283-285)
      - Annual meeting, 1947-1948 (Box 27, Folder 286)
      - Connecticut Public Health Nursing Association, 1947-1948 (Box 27, Folder 287)
    - National Research Council, 1947-1948 (Box 27, Folder 288)
    - National Sanitation Foundation, 1947-1948 (Box 27, Folder 289)
    - National Sanitation Foundation, 1947-1948 (Box 28, Folder 290)
    - National Society for the Prevention of Blindness, 1947-1948 (Box 28, Folder 291-294)
    - National Society for the Prevention of Blindness, 1947-1948 (Box 29, Folder 295)
      - Committee on Program (Plan & Scope), 1947-1948 (Box 29, Folder 296)
    - National Tuberculosis Association, 1947-1948 (Box 29, Folder 297-299)
      - Connecticut Tuberculosis Association, 1947-1948 (Box 29, Folder 300)
      - New Haven Tuberculosis Association, 1947-1948 (Box 29, Folder 301)
      - New Haven Tuberculosis Association, 1947-1948 (Box 30, Folder 302-303)
      - Planning Committee, Third National Conference on College Health, 1947-1948 (Box 30, Folder 304)
    - New England Health Institute, 1947-1948 (Box 30, Folder 305)
    - New Haven Board of Health, 1947-1948 (Box 30, Folder 306-307)
    - New Haven Board of Health: minutes of meetings, 1947-1948 (Box 31, Folder 308)
    - New Haven Board of Health: Health Education Committee, 1947-1948 (Box 31, Folder 309)
    - New Haven Council of Social Agencies, 1947-1948 (Box 31, Folder 310)
    - New Haven Hospital, 1947-1948 (Box 31, Folder 311)
    - New Haven Hospital: Grace-New Haven Community Hospital Building Fund, 1947-1948 (Box 31, Folder 312)
    - New Haven Junior League, 1947-1948 (Box 31, Folder 313)
    - New Haven School Survey, 1947-1948 (Box 31, Folder 314)
    - New Haven Visiting Nurse Association, 1947-1948 (Box 31, Folder 315)
    - Rockefeller Foundation, 1947-1948 (Box 31, Folder 316)
    - Society of American Bacteriologists, 1947-1948 (Box 31, Folder 317)
    - United States Army, 1947-1948 (Box 31, Folder 318-319)
    - United States Army, 1947-1948 (Box 32, Folder 320)
      - Civil Affairs Division, 1947-1948 (Box 32, Folder 321)
      - Civil Affairs Training School, 1947-1948 (Box 32, Folder 322)
    - United States Navy, 1947-1948 (Box 32, Folder 323)
    - United States Department of Agriculture, 1947-1948 (Box 32, Folder 324)
    - United States Government: Education, 1947-1948 (Box 32, Folder 325)
    - United States Public Health Service, 1947-1948 (Box 32, Folder 326-329)
    - United States Public Health Service, 1947-1948 (Box 33, Folder 330)
      - Bolton Fellowships, 1947-1948 (Box 33, Folder 331)
      - Venereal Disease Study, 1947-1948 (Box 33, Folder 332-334)
      - Cancer Project, 1947-1948 (Box 33, Folder 335)
      - Mental Hygiene Division, 1947-1948 (Box 33, Folder 336)
    - Health Departments [City, County, State], 1947-1948 (Box 33, Folder 337-338)
    - Health Departments [City, County, State], 1947-1948 (Box 34, Folder 339)
    - Health Department: New York City Health Dept., 1947-1948 (Box 34, Folder 340)
    - Health Department: Mississippi State Board of Health, 1947-1948 (Box 34, Folder 341)
    - Widdemer, Kenneth D, 1947-1948 (Box 34, Folder 342)
    - World Health Organization of the United Nations, 1947-1948 (Box 34, Folder 343)
    - Y.M.C.A. and Y.W.C.A., 1947-1948 (Box 34, Folder 344)
  - 1948-1949
    - General A (Box 35, Folder 345-347)
    - General B (Box 35, Folder 348-349)
    - General C (Box 36, Folder 351-352, Box 35, Folder 350)
    - General D (Box 36, Folder 353)
    - General E (Box 36, Folder 354)
    - General F (Box 36, Folder 355)
    - General G (Box 36, Folder 356)
    - General H (Box 36, Folder 357)
    - General I (Box 36, Folder 358)
    - General J (Box 37, Folder 359)
    - General K (Box 37, Folder 360)
    - General L (Box 37, Folder 361)
    - General M (Box 37, Folder 362)
    - General N (Box 37, Folder 363-366)
    - General O (Box 38, Folder 367)
    - General P (Box 38, Folder 368)
    - General R (Box 38, Folder 369)